欢迎来到vite系统
welcome to the vite system
一个关于合作的故事
a story about collaboration
我在escabaletto也被称为patak
I'm at the escabaletto also known as patak
我是beatcore团队的一员
I am part of the beatcore team
我在stagrits工作
and I work at the stagrits
在那里我可以花时间专注于节拍。
where I get to spend my time focusing on beat
我很高兴今天能参加vidconth的活动
I am very happy to be at vidconth today
我们将听到
we're going to hear
我们会听到很多项目的名称和概念。
about a lot of project names and concept in this talk
如果你不了解这些，不要担心。
don't worry if you don't understand them all
让我们试着把注意力集中在大的方面，即
let's try to focus on the big picture of
成为一个生态系统的一部分意味着什么？
what it means to be part of an ecosystem
以及各项目之间的关系
and the relationship between the projects
在每个标志的背后都有
also behind each of the logos there is
有很多人参与其中
a lot of people involved
这个故事是关于他们的
this story is about them
玻璃是一个孤立的发展
vit is an develop in isolation
这实际上是
this is actually part
我们宇宙中相互联系的社区的一部分
of our universe of interconnected communities
和节拍的对话
and the beat conversation
今天就是一个很好的例子
today is a great example of that
你将会听到狗
you're going to hear dogs
从大多数小册子的容器中
from the containers of most of the brochure
我们将在这里检查
we are going to check here
所以，如果你想了解更多关于他们的信息，请继续关注。
so stay tuned if you want to learn more about them
的
the
和
and
他是什叶派的传统工具的一部分
he's part of a tradition of shia's tools
在什叶派的系统中
in the shia's system
webpak
是下面的
was the below
在那个时候，模块
at a time where modules
浏览器上甚至不支持模块
weren't even supported on the browser
weback Tim
the weback Tim
必须要克服很多复杂的问题
had to overcome a lot of complexity
他们还需要一个非常灵活的工具
they also needed a very flexible tool
因为很多我们现在认为是理所当然的
because a lot of the batters and convention
我们现在认为是理所当然的
that we now give for granted
还没有出现
weren't there yet
卷起蒂姆
the roll up Tim
做出了巨大的先进的人在树上摇晃
made huge advanced man in tree shaking
并开发了一个直观和灵活的API
and also develop an intuitive and flexibleplug in API
来扩展它
to extend it
拓展了index atml的概念。
parcel popularize the idea of the index atml
作为你的应用程序的中心
as the center of your application
以及故障和0配置的理念。
and also of saint a fault and 0 config
在可能的情况下
wherever possible
有一个新的品种
there is a new breed
用消极的语言编写工具
oftools write it in negative language
例如，swc
for example swc
这是一个很好的替代方案。
that is a rast alternative to a well
或es Bill
or es Bill
一个支持骰子蠕动的Shays的捆绑器。
a go bundler for shays that also supports dice creep
和沙耶性
and shaya sex
这些本地工具可以达到
these native tools achieve as speeds that
是不可能的。
were impossible on chase land
小麦是一个新的
wheat is part of a new
的一部分。
wave of tools
在天鹅绒时代，唐-班杜被告知
that during the velope man don bandu are told
我们使用现代浏览器中的模块支持
we use the module support in modern browsers
来启动一个深度服务器
to fire up a depth server
来传输模块
that transpires modules on the fly
将它们提供给浏览器
serving them to the browser
而且我们可以实现
and we can achieve
即时反馈，因为我们可以有
instant feedback because we can have
在模块层面上的模型替换
both model replacement at the module level
网络深度服务器
web depth server
雪园wmr
snow park wmr
它们都是这些工具浪潮中的一部分
they are all part of these wave of tools
而且它们彼此之间有很大的影响
and they heavily influence each other
例如，wmr
for example wmr
是第一个提出通用的
the first to introduce the idea of a universal
像插件的API
roll up like plugin API
同时适用于深入的
that works with both in depth
和构建同时进行
and build at the same time
后来
that later on
采用
adopted
维生素
vit
是我们共同系统中其他工具的一个指示
is an instruction of our other tools in the co system
在比尔时代
during Bill time
你可以把它看成是一个有意见的
you can think about it as an opinionated
为卷起的设置
setup for roll up
我们尽可能地使用es Bill来加快处理速度
we use es Bill wherever we can to speed up processing
例如，对CSS和shas进行最小化，或者剥离
for example minification of CSS and shas or stripping
类型
types
我们采取一种务实的方法
and we take a pragmatic approach
我们不需要barbell
we don't need barbell
在所有情况下，但
in all cases but
但对于支持所有浏览器的传统插件来说
for plugging legacy to support all the browsers
我们会向它伸出援手
we'll reach out to it
我们也使用os CSS
we also use os CSS
在内部处理CSS
process CSS internally
也是为了更好地与CSS标准接轨
and also to better align with CSS standards
使用Ved时
when using ved
保护自己免受生态系统变化的影响
are guarding yourself against changes in the ecosystem
例如，我们可以在未来将valvel改为sdc
for example we could change valvel to sdc in the future
和包裹团队
and the parcel team
的汽车现在发布它
cars now release it
照明CSS
lighting CSS
这是一个Ross流程的替代方案，而不是占有CSS
that is a Ross process alternative to poss CSS
我们也可以采用它来加快CSS的处理速度
we could also adopt it to speed up CSS processing
现在，我们对ES的建设非常满意
and right now we are very happy with es build
但是，如果一致走向swc
butif the consistent move towards swc
我们可能最终也会取代它作为内部建设
we may end up also replacing it as building internally
和
and
所有这些
all of these
都可以在不影响用户的情况下完成
can be done with little disruption or users
而且
and
我不知道这是否会是
I don't know if this is going to be
我们在未来会使用的
those we will use in the future
但你要么
but you either
因此，小麦中的那个东西实际上
so that thing in wheat actually
再一次帮助你防范这些变化
again help you guard again these changes
小麦对视图有很大的支持
wheat has great support for view
项目预案
project preact
svelt leat
solid和其他许多UI框架
solid and many others UI frameworks
实际上
actually the
这些框架的团队
teams from these frameworks
都参与了小麦团的开发。
are involved in the development of wheat corps
而且我们有非常好的
and we have really good
所有这些的健康模型替换
health model replacement for all of them
这使得像 astro 这样的工具
this allows tools like astro
等工具可以建立在小麦的基础上，并专注于新的功能
to build on top of wheat and focus on new features
或
or
探索新的架构，如小岛的架构
explore new architecture like island's architecture
Astra不需要重新雇用
Astra doesn't need to re employment
一切
everything
的框架和维护者已经在小麦中完成的工作。
that is already done in wheat by the frameworks and
小麦公司的维护者
the maintainers of wheat corp
故事书的目标是一样的
the same goal for a storybook
那
that
想象一下，如果一个故事书必须要重新创建
actually imagine if a storybook will have to recreate
所有这些
everything that
这些框架所做的一切
have been done by these frameworks
我们可以在一个较低的水平上分享
and we get to share at a lower level
因为卷轴式贝斯插件的API非常灵活
because the roll up bass plug in API is very flexible
因此，我们可以有比如说
so we can have for example
与plagium PW a
with plagium PW a
来抽象出我们框架中对PW a的支持
to abstract the support for PW a in our frameworks
或者
or
我的插件，以增加党镇的速度
I plug in to add party town to a speed up
sur party discretes
或
or
我插入了uno CSS
I plug in for uno CSS
在SSR框架中也有很多的创新
and there is also a lot of innovation in ssr frameworks
在视图方面
on the view side
我们有knacks，在其
we have knacks that in its
sard版本中采用了weed的错误。
sard version has adopted weed by the fault
但这真的很有趣，因为他们
but it was really interesting because they
实际上是在一个障碍物中创建
actually create in an obstruction
让用户选择网络公园或小麦
that lets user choose web park or wheat
而在这个过程中
and in the process
他们创建了一套库
they created a set of libraries
在这个过程中，他们创建了一套库，在安凯的保护伞下
under the anchaeus umbrella
其他人后来也可以用它来实现同样的目的
that others can later use to achieve the same
嘿
hey
在反应方面
on the react side
我们有idroshan
we have idroshan
这是一个框架，由shopify开发
that is a frame or developed by shopify
为电子商务开发的
for e commerce
他们正在与反应团队合作，以确保
and they are working with the react team to ensure
他们正在与反应团队合作，以确保反应组件在Vit上正常工作。
that reacts are components work properly on vit
在这个焊缝方面，他们正在研究它的velkit
on this weld side they are working on its velkit
和
and
因为velkit是相当重要的，因为ssr
as velkit is quite important because the ssr
基元，我们现在都在享受这些基元
primitives that we all enjoy right now
是
were
的一部分而开发的。
originally developed as part of
的一部分，当时它正在使用snowback
as veldkit when it was using snowback
和
and
在固体方面，我们有固体开始
on the solid side we have solid start
和
and
还有许多小麦压榨机是一个静态尺寸发生器
so many more wheat press is a static size generator
基于view和wheat
based on view and wheat
的静态尺寸发生器，我们在生态系统的很多文件中使用
that we use in a lot of documentations
生态系统中
in the ecosystem
快速团队的快速城市
quick city from the quick team
一个类似的东西，它是一个Angular amp的小麦
an analog that is an angular amp wheat
框架
framework
我们说的小行星
asteroid we say
和更多的岛屿
and many more isles
将X分类，并将其与塞满的SR拉卡分类。
classify the x with pluginess SR rakas
和
and
维生素从图片中消失
vit disappears from the picture
大量的用户将
a lot of users are going
通过一个框架来体验维生素
to experience vit through a framework
事实上，大多数人都是如此
most of them actually
但所有这些框架
but all these frameworks
一起合作
get to collaborate together
来改善衬衫工具
into improving the shirt tool
因此，这是一个非0变焦的游戏
so this is a non 0 zoom game
每个人都能得到一个更好的工具
everybody gets a better tool
我们还举行了一个关于测试的素食者协议
we also held a vegan pact on testing
剧作家和赛普拉斯
playwright and Cypress
卡斯采用了小麦
Cass adopted wheat
为他们的组件测试的新功能
for their new features of component testing
在测试方面，它是一个原生的、替代胸部的工具。
on the test is a native with alternative to chest
它实际上是为自己的生态系统服务的。
and it actually does serve an ecosystem talk of its own
它已经看到了大量的采用
it's seen a huge amount of adoption
它已经被大量采用，并可能成为推动脚踏实地的主要动力之一。
and is going to be probably one of the main
它已被大量采用，并可能成为推动脚步前进的主要动力之一。
drivers of adoption of feet moving forward
你也可以用它来测试节点
you can use it also to test node
例如，Remix
and for example the remix
正在使用wheatas和他们的启动器
are using wheatas and their starters
但他们并没有使用小麦
but they are not using wheat
和
and
测试可以享受到
the test get to enjoy the
快速的热模型替换，用于你的单元测试
fast hot model replacement on feed for your unit tests
所以你可以得到这种即时反馈
so you get this instant feedback
我们现在在开发时就有这样的反馈
that we have while developing now
当你检查你的测试时
while you check your tests
和
and
我们正处于一个新的Shayes环境时代的到来。
we are in the down of a new era of shayes environments
没有Shayes不再是孤独的了
no shayes is no longer alone
你有其他的环境，比如他们知道
you have other environments like they know
或禁止
or a ban
和
and
网络容器从一个小堆栈，导致你运行
webcontainers from a stacklet that led you ran
在浏览器中没有shayes
no shayes in the browser
四叶草工人和其他边缘网络
Clover workers and other edge networks
和
and
所有这些环境都非常关心
all of this environment care a lot
关于适当的维生素支持
about proper vit support
因为它的影响力
because of the reach
我们之前看到的一个框架系统
a system of framework that we saw before
如果他们得到了vitworking的支持
if they get vitworking on them
他们就会有很多的用户
they are going to get a lot of users
所以有很多的合作
so there is a lot of collaboration
所以在小麦和这些
between wheat and these
环境和这些团队之间的合作
environments and these teams
我们还需要部署我们的应用程序
we also need to deploy our applications
为此，我们需要服务有
and for that we need the services to have
对我们所建工具的开箱即用的支持
out of the box support for our built tools
我们已经看到了这一点。
and we are seeing this already with vit
netly 5 versail
Clover workers firebase
可能会简化它，然后是其他一个
probably simplify it then one others
我们非常关心为小麦提供一个好的
care a lot about giving a good
小麦的用户故事
user story for wheat
例如，nellify已经创建了一个插件。
for example nellify has created a plugin with plug in
所以框架可以
so frameworks can
以更简单的方式使用他们的边缘网络
use their edge network in an easier way
小麦也被视为大量采用
wheat is also seen a lot of adoption
伞状框架上
on the umbakand frameworks
小麦的先锋Ruvi
pioneer by wheat ruvi
显示，你可以使用vid来获得
thatshow that you can use vid to get
即时反馈，同时开发骑行请求
instant feedback while developing ride supplications
这为laravel的发展铺平了道路
this pave the way for laravel
现在采用vid作为他们的默认版本
now adopted vid as their default
这对Vita来说是一个巨大的选择
this is huge for vita option
让我们来关注一下其中的一个子生态系统
let's focus on one of the sub ecosystems
故事的生态系统
the story's ecosystem
在这里，我们必须要对故事书给予很大的肯定
we have to give a lot of credit to a storybook here
因为他们为故事创造了一个开放的标准
because they created an open standard for stories that
它正在受益于
it's benefiting
像这个生态系统
like this ecosystem
小麦降低了创建一个新故事的门槛，就像
wheat lower the barrier for creating a new story like
一个故事书，如弗兰克的作品
a storybook like frank work
所以我们看到了像《维塔沃克的故事》这样的弗兰克作品。
so we are seeing franks like is histoire vitwook laddle
和
and
他们都可以尝试新的想法
they all get to try new ideas
我们还看到
we are also seeing
previewshayes和volar是vs代码的扩展。
previewshayes and volar that are vs code extensions
但他们在内部使用小麦
but they use wheat internally
来实时预览你所开发的组件
to preview components in real time what you develop
有点像线上故事
kind of like in line stories
和
and
也是为什么框架
also why frame
这给了
that gives
原始的村民自己的故事书
primitive to vill your own storybook
和
and
这对故事书本身有很大的好处
this has a lot of benefits for a storybook itself
因为一个故事书可以看到它
because a storybook gets to see it
别人在做什么，什么是不可行的，而且
what others are doing and what works are not and
他们以后可以采用你
they can later adopt you
故事书现在也在大量使用视频。
storybook is also using vid a lot now
Anvit也有违反其他社区的情况
anvit also has breaches to other communities that
不是直接下游的
are not directly downstream
下游或上游项目
downstream or upstream projects
例如，bmpm有大量的使用。
for example there is a lot of usage of bmpm
和相关项目的使用。
on with related projects
和
and
在bmpm的价值方面有很多的一致性
there is a lot of alignment in the values of bmpm
比如说pmpm是一个非常
like is a pmpm is a very
是一个非常快速和有效的公园灰烬管理器
fast and efficient park ash manager
还有
also
故事是
story is
它可以让你创建
that lets you create
停止应用程序
the stop applications
形成不同的模具，高效安全
that are various mold and efficient and secure
他们内部也在使用小麦
they are also using wheat internally
所以与他们合作是有意义的
so it makes sense to collaborate with them
为游乐场的功能提供了雏形
staglets for the playground feature
他们需要他们的应用程序立即启动
they need their applications to start right away
而v深度服务器的按需使用特性
and the on demand nature
v深度服务器对这种使用情况来说是非常好的。
of the v depth server is amazing for that use case
因为你可以在
because you get in
在一瞬间
in a split second
一个游乐场工作
a playground working
所以我们已经看到很多人采用了 "契约"。
so we have seen a lot of adoption of deed
例如，在文件中尝试
for example in documenttemptation
游乐场和例子
playgrounds and examples
权力，作者：ESTAGLITZ
power by estaglitz
所以你可以在你的浏览器中打开它们
so you can open them in your browser
再如维生素
again vit
是一种发展中的绝缘体
is a developing insulation
坑是一个
pit is part of a
巨大的工具和框架的生态系统的一部分。
huge ecosystem of tools and frameworks and plaguines
所有这些项目一起工作
and all these projects work together
协作并分享想法和模式
to collaborate and share ideas and patterns
我们实际上还没有触及到这个生态系统的表面
we actually didn't scratch the surface of
这个生态系统的范围有多大
how reach all this ecosystem is
而且
and
这又是关于人与人之间的合作
again this is about people people working together
互相帮助
helping each other
而这是很难复制的
and this is really difficult to replicate
一个生态系统
an ecosystem
是一个开源项目的最佳资产之一
is one of the best assets of an open source project
所以
so
同样
again
这个
this
阶段
stage of wheatcomp
的这个阶段对我们来说真的很重要，在这个时候
is really important for us at this moment
我们一直在一起工作
we have worked together
在这段时间里，我非常希望看到
during all this time and I am eager to see
所有的维护者展示他们是如何使用小麦的
all the maintainers show how they are using wheat
以及他们带来了哪些新的想法
and what new ideas they bring to the table
我希望我们能继续合作
and I hope we can continue to collaborate
和
and
分享
share
模式、想法和代码
patterns and ideas and code
并创造一些
and create something that is bigger
比我们每个人的项目都要大。
than each of our projects
我想感谢我们的团队和贡献者们
I want to thanks a lot the with team and contributors
还有Lagins、框架和工具的维护者们
also the maintainers of lagins and frameworks and tools
不断互相帮助的社区
the communities that are helping each other constantly
以及
and
还有vitcom的演讲者和合作者
also the vitcom speakers and collaborators
我知道他们在所有的演讲中付出了多少努力
I know how much effort they put in all the talks
和
and
交错的团队
the staggered team
和社区合作伙伴，使之成为可能
and community partner for making become possible
这真的是一个梦想成真
this is really a dream come true
祝你在接下来的会议中愉快
and enjoy a lot the rest of the conference
我们将在论坛上见
and see you in discord
我们将在那里讨论所有的会谈。
and we are going to discuss all the talks there